Hello, and welcome to Lesson 9 of this introduction to calculus with Wolfram U.
您好，欢迎来到 Wolfram U 的微积分入门课程第9课。
Our topic for today is differentiation formulas. Let’s begin with a brief overview of today’s lesson.
今天我们的主题是求导公式。 让我们从今天课程的简要概述开始。
The point is that one can find derivatives using the limit definition, but in practice
关键是可以使用极限定义来计算导数，但实际上这是
this is quite a tedious and tricky approach, and one wishes that there was some simpler way
一种繁琐而棘手的方法，我们希望在实际计算时有更简单的方法
of finding derivatives in practice. Luckily there are formulas which help us to find derivatives
幸运的是，有一些公式可以帮助我们计算许多常见函数的导数。
of many commonly occurring functions. For example, here is a constant function f[x] = c,
例如，这是一个常数函数 f[x] =  c ，
and you can see over here that the derivative of this function is just 0. The derivative of
并且您可以在此处看到该函数的导数为 0。
a constant function is always 0. Let’s check the graphs. Here is a graph of the function,
常数函数的导数始终为 0。让我们检查一下图。这是函数的图像，
and the derivative is 0. In this lesson, what we’ll do is we’ll cover basic differentiation formulas
导数为 0。在本课中，我们将介绍这种类型的基本求导公式，
of this type, and by the end of today’s lesson, you’ll feel quite comfortable about
到本课结束时，您将对
computing derivatives in practice.
在实践中计算导数感到十分舒适。
As a first example, here are the power functions. You have a function x^n.
作为第一个例子，这是幂函数。 您有一个 x^n 函数。
For different values of n, you get different power functions. Taking this function
对于 n 的不同取值，您将获得不同的幂函数。 用这个函数
and finding its derivative gives you n * x^(n − 1). That’s a very well-known formula
计算它的导数可以得到  n * x^(n − 1) 。 这是一个非常著名的公式
in differential calculus. For example, if n is 2, then you have a quadratic function
在微积分中。 例如，如果 n 为2，则您得到一个二次函数，其导数为
and its derivative is just 2x. It might be good to memorize that the derivative of x^2 is 2x.
2x 最好记住 x^2 的导数是 2x
Let’s plot the function and derivative. That’s the function, a quadratic function, a parabola,
让我们绘制函数和导数。
and that’s the derivative, and clearly the derivative must be negative on the left
那是函数，二次函数，抛物线，这是导数，显然，导数在左边必须为负
because the function is decreasing, so the slopes are all negative over here.
因为函数在减小，所以这里的斜率都是负的。
Going to the same topic, suppose you have x^−1. That’s a negative number,
转到同一主题的另一个例子，假设您有 x^−1。指数是一个负数，
but the same rule applies and you get back −1/x^2 as the answer. Again, here is a plot of the function
但是同样的规则依旧适用，并且您得到的答案为 −1/x^2 。再次，这是函数的图像
and its derivative. Finally let’s take an example where you actually have
及其导数。 最后，让我们举个例子
a kind of negative decimal power. But the same formula applies, and you get back
一种指数为负小数的幂函数。 但是，使用相同的公式，就可以得到
a derivative in the same form, n * x^(n − 1).
相同形式的导数 n * x^(n − 1)。
Okay. To go further, let’s now talk about constant multiples of functions. Here you have
好的。 为了更进一步，让我们现在谈谈常数乘函数的导数。
a constant and a function, and when you try to find the derivative, what you do is you simply
在这里，您有一个常数和一个函数，当您尝试计算导数时，您所做的就是
pull out the constant from the function where you’re trying finding the derivative.
从要求导的函数中提出常数。
The derivative over here is just 15x^2, which is just 5 times 3x^2, so the 15x^2 over here
此处的导数为 15x^2，是 3x^2 的 5 倍，因此此处的 15x^2
the constant 5 times 3x^2, which is the derivative of x^3. Here’s a plot of the function and derivative,
也就是常数 5 乘以 3x^2，后者是 x^^3 的导数。这是函数和导数的图像，
and you can see that this is a very simple rule, the constant multiple rule.
您会看到这是一个非常简单的规则，即数乘规则。
To go a step further, let’s look at a very important rule named the sum rule.
为了更进一步，让我们来看一个非常重要的规则，即求和规则。
If you have a function f and a function g and you find their sum, then the derivative of the sum
如果您有一个函数 f 和一个函数 g
is just the sum of the derivatives. So you simply work out f' and g' separately,
并计算它们的和，则和的导数就是导数的和。因此，您只需分别计算 f' 和 g'，
and then when you add them up, in this case you get back 6x + 2, which is the correct answer.
然后将它们加起来，在这种情况下，您会得到 6x + 2，这是正确的答案。
The sum rule makes it quite simple to find the derivative in such cases. Once again, here’s a plot.
在这种情况下，求和规则使查找导数变得非常简单。 我们再次画图。
You have the function f[x], the function g[x], and the derivatives over here are f'[x],  g'[x],
您有函数 f[x]，函数 g[x]，导数是 f'[x],  g'[x],
and the sum has got a derivative, which is the sum of those two.
，求和为另一个导数，即, 这两个导数的总和。
Okay. On to the difference rule, which is very simple and similar.
好的。 关于求差规则也非常简单且相似。
If you’ve got a function f and a function g and you define their difference,
如果您有一个函数 f 和一个函数 g
then then derivative of the difference is the difference of the derivatives—
并定义了它们的差，那么该差的导数就是导数的差，
namely, you work out f'[x], work out g'[x] and then you subtract them, and you get back
即，您计算出 f'[ x]，计算出 g'[x]，然后
the answer for the difference derivative. Here’s a plot of all the derivatives. Once again you see that
相减，然后您会得到函数差的导数。这是所有导数的图像。再一次看到
if you have a difference, then the derivative is really simple to compute.
如果你有两个函数的差构成的的新函数，则该函数导数的计算非常简单。
Sums are simple. Differences are simple. The question is what happens to products.
求和很简单。 做差很简单。 问题是两个函数相乘会发生什么。
Well, if you have a function f[x] and then a function g[x] and you multiply them to get the product,
好吧，如果您有一个函数 f[x] 然后有一个函数 g[x] 然后相乘得到积
you might think that the derivative of the product is the product of the derivatives,
您可能会认为积的导数是导数的积，
but that is not the case. In fact, if you work it out over here you get √x in one case
但事实并非如此。实际上，如果在这里进行计算，则在一种情况下会得到 √x，
and you get quite a different answer in the other. It turns out that in this case,
而在另一种情况下会得到完全不同的答案。事实证明，在这种情况下，
the correct formula is you do f * g' + g * f', and then you do get back the correct answer
正确的公式是 f * g' + g * f'，然后你就得到了
for the derivative of the product. Once again, here’s a plot of all three derivatives
函数积的导数的正确答案。我们再次画图, 这是所有三个导数的图像
to give you a feeling for what’s happening over here, but notice that now things are no longer simple.
图像让您对这些情况有感觉，但是请注意，现在事情不再简单了。
You actually do need to memorize a rule which says that the derivative of
您实际上确实需要记住一条规则，该规则说 f 和 g
the product of f and g is f * g' + g * f', and as if this is not complicated enough,
的乘积的导数是 f * g'+ g * f'，好像还不够复杂，
let’s look at the quotient rule. If you have f and g and you take their quotient,
让我们看一下商规则。 如果您有 f 和 g
so you divide them, then once again the derivative of the quotient is not the quotient of the derivatives.
并取它们的商，也就是将它们相除，则商的导数不是该导数的商。
You can check that over here. If you do f'/g', you get one answer;
您可以在这里检查。 如果您执行 f' / g'，则会得到一个答案；
if you find the derivative directly for the quotient, you get another answer.
如果直接计算商的导数，则会得到另一个答案。
The fact is that the quotient rule for derivatives is a lot harder. It says that
事实是，导数的商规则要难得多。它表明导数是
the derivative is (g * f' − f * g')/g^2. In this case, the rule gives you the correct answer,
(g * f' − f * g')/g^2。在这种情况下，商规则会为您提供正确的答案，
namely, −3/2x^3. Once again you can plot all the derivatives, and you learn that the quotient rule
即，-3/2x^3。再一次，您可以绘制所有导数，并且您会发现
is significantly more complicated than the earlier rules, but in fact it does give you
商规则比以前的规则复杂得多，但实际上，它确实可以给您
the correct answer in all cases. We’ve learned the sum rule, the difference rule, the product rule
在所有情况下的正确答案。
and the quotient rule, and in fact that brings us to the end of today’s lesson.
我们已经学习了求和规则，求差规则，乘积规则和商规则，实际上，这使我们到今天的课程结束。
The point is that yes, derivatives are useful, but it is only when you have the rules for differentiation
关键是，是的，导数是有用的，但是只有当您具有导数规则时，
that you can actually use them effectively in practice, so you do need to know all the rules we learned today.
您才能在实践中实际有效地使用它们，因此您确实需要了解我们今天学到的所有规则。
There are rules for sums, differences, products and quotients. Of course the simplest rule is the power rule,
对于和，差，积和商有规则。当然，最简单的规则是幂规则，
which lets you find the derivative of things like x^2 and x^3 and other powers of x.
这样您就可以计算 x^2 和 x^3 之类的导数以及 x 的其他幂的导数。
In the next lesson, we’ll go on to doing something more with derivatives, namely,
在下一课中，我们将继续对导数做更多的事情，
talking about the trigonometric functions. But before we do that,
即谈论三角函数的导数。但是在我们这样做之前
do make sure you review today’s lesson, try the exercises and make sure
请确保您复习了今天的课程，尝试一下练习，
you’re ready for the next theme, which is the derivatives of trigonometric functions.
并确保您准备好下一个主题（三角函数的导数主题）。
I’ll stop over here. I hope you found this lesson really useful. This is where calculus really begins,
我在这里停下来。 我希望您感到本课非常有用。这是微积分真正开始的地方，
where it becomes a very algebraic kind of process and becomes easy to apply in practice.
从此微积分的计算成为一种非常代数化的过程，并且易于在实践中应用。
Thank you very much. I’ll stop over here.
非常感谢你。 我在这里停下来。
(翻译: 秦晋 北京师范大学)